Sanjay Jewalikar

Technical Manager

Union City, CA - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Sanjay-Jewalikar/404a240b693eca99

A career Driven IT Management Professional with solid technical and Management experience in large scale high volume business environments. Adept at designing solutioning implementing and managing IT projects.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Technical Manager

- September 2012 to May 2017

Providing strategic direction for application deployment Standards across all the Oracle products in OMCS (Oracle Managed Cloud Services) environment.

- Serve as OMCS change management and IT operations lead for SOC/PCI/FedRAMP audit.
- Project lead on BTM (Business Transaction Monitoring) project for OMCS
- Solution Design, Capacity Planning, Implementation Planning and Managing Oracle Agile PLM implementation, Migration and upgrade for OMCS Agile customers.
- Solution Design, Capacity Planning, Implementation Planning and Managing implementation, migration and upgrade for OPLA/OBIEE for OMCS customers.
- Solution Design, Capacity Planning, Implementation Planning and Managing implementation for SOA, B2B, AIA and FMW for OMCS customers.
- Production and implementation support for Agile PLM, OPLA OMCS customers

IT Application Architect/Administrator

Lab126 (Amazon) - October 2011 to September 2012

Lab126 is a division of Amazon company that designs and engineers high-profile, portable, hand-held consumer electronics products.

- Designed and managed migration of Agile PLM 9.3.1.1 from lab126 to Amazon data center.
- Implemented Oracle Database for Agile PLM in Amazon's Oracle Production Database Fabric.
- Implemented Oracle Product Data quality (PDQ) in Amazon Production Fabric.
- Designed and Implemented application and Database Backup on Amazon web Services.
- Production support to IT applications like Libsync, Agile, OPLA/OBIEE, Provision, EC, Proe.
- Designed OBIEE/OPLA Implementation in Amazon Production Fabric.

IT Application Manager/ Engineering Manager/Staff Systems Specialist

Tellabs Inc - November 1999 to September 2011

Tellabs is an industry-leading designer and manufacturer of next-generation telecom network equipment. Enterprise Global Applications Architect.

- Designed and Managed Global Implementation of Agile PLM 9.2 PC, PCM, and PG&C Modules (Four US locations and two locations in Europe).
- Designed, Managed and supported Global Implementation of PTC Windchill PDMLink 9.0, Arbortext.
- Expert in Application installation, patching, upgrades, configuration & troubleshooting.
- Solid knowledge of Application Server 9iAS & 10gAS, Weblogic 10 & 11Gr2, Apache/Tomcat / J2EE.
- Designed, Implemented and Administrating Oracle Database cluster 10g, 11G.
- Directly handled all equipment and Software Licenses negotiations and purchasing.
- Designed and managed Implementation of Veritas Backup and SAN solution.
- Managing implementation of Virtual servers (VMware) for the engineering applications.

- · Managed technical Implementation of Supply Chain management.
- Designed and Managed Implementation of Test Automation and Test Management. (Quality Center).
- · Managed Implementation of Knowledge management for customer support.
- Managed and developed interfaces between different applications as per business requirement.
- Managed Implementation and Administration of Remedy (CRM).

Sr. Oracle Database Administrator/Consultant

GRIC Communications, Inc - June 1999 to October 1999

GRIC Communications provides an IP services platform and clearinghouse.

My responsibilities were

- Shell scripting and PL/ Sql scripting for database administration.
- Tuning of production, development and staging databases.
- Database Backup & Recovery.
- Database support to developers and users.

Sr. Oracle Database Administrator/Consultant

Retail, Inc - January 1999 to May 1999

ISR is a new Internet based food and grocery selling.

My responsibilities were

- Shell scripting and PL/Sql scripting for database administration.
- Tuning of production, development and staging databases.
- Database support to developers and users.
- Database Backup & Recovery.

UNIX Administrator/Oracle Database Administrator

GUTHY-RENKER, CA - May 1998 to December 1998

Guthy-Renker is in info-commercial business

My responsibilities were:

- · Backup & recovery
- Monitoring and analyzing the database performance.
- Shell scripting and PL/Sql scripting for database administration.
- Monitoring the oracle application using concurrent request processing and tuning.
- · Administration of oracle application.
- · Administration of HP-UX.

Project Manager

CMC Ltd - September 1994 to April 1998

Unit Trust of India

This project relates to the implementation of custom software product developed by CMC for Unit Trust of India. This software product helps Unit Trust of India to manage sales and post sales support and services of Mutual Fund(s) Unit. This Implementation was across 58 branches spreaded across India.

Managed Implementation of custom built software.

- Project Management and managed team of ten UNIX administrators and Database administrators.
- Planning, allocating and designing the database structure of the application.

Pimpri -Chinchwad Muncipal Corporation, India

Integrated Octroi (a local tax levied on interstate movement of goods in India) Management System, Maharashtra State Government On-line Octroi collection and receipt generation at twenty-five offices and sending data to central office for various report generations.

Managed Turn key implementation of Octroi Management System.

- Software Requirement Specification, System Design, System Test Design document.
- Project Management, Resource management.
- Pre proposal study.
- Selection of RDBMS, OS, GUI development tools.
- · Hardware selection.
- Planning, allocating and designing the database structure of the application in Oracle Asymmetric replication environment.

CMC Ltd - Pune, Maharashtra - September 1986 to April 1998

CMC Limited is a leading IT solutions company and a subsidiary of Tata Consultancy Services Limited (TCS Ltd), one of the world's leading information technology consulting, services and business process outsourcing organizations.

Sr. Systems Administrator/ Software Developer

Government of India - September 1991 to August 1994

Irrigation Department, Government of India

A comprehensive system for the planning, design, construction, monitoring, operation and maintenance of irrigation schemes for Irrigation Department. This Project was funded by World Bank.

- Preparation of System Software Requirement Specification, System Design, System Test Design documents.
- Design and Development of Integrated Agricultural development Module
- Design and Development of Communication Module for data transfer between different Irrigation offices using Modem
- Implementation of MIS at various Irrigation offices.

Database/ UNIX/Network Administrator

Kirloskar Oil Engines - Pune, Maharashtra - September 1986 to August 1991

India

Administration Support for Payroll System, Manufacturing system, and Finance system.

- Installation of UNIX, Oracle and its application tools.
- Planning, allocating and designing the database structure of the application.
- Monitoring and analyzing the database performance and tuning the database.
- Planning and taking Database backups.
- Developed UNIX shell utilities for System and Database Administration.

IUCAA, Pune, India

Administration Support for SUN Solaris.

- Installation, configuration and Networking the Hardware.
- Configuring O.S. and TCP/IP connectivity.
- Solaris, Network Administration and maintenance.
- · Maintaining Access levels.
- Backup and restore the files/raw devices using tar, cpio, dd, and dump.
- Monitor the load on the system and tune the O.S. and network.

Indian Meteorological Department, Government of India

Installation, Configuration and Administration of DEC VAX 4000/300.

- Installation, configuration, System Administration of VAX 4000/300 in cluster.
- The Network constituted connectivity between VMS, UNIX and DOS Operating.

EDUCATION

Oracle University

SKILLS

Apache (10+ years), Oracle (10+ years), Tomcat (10+ years), UNIX (9 years), Weblogic (10+ years)

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Technical Skills

Languages Visual Basic 6, C, Java, SQL, PL/SQL, Unix Shell script (awk, sed)

Operating Systems Windows UNIX (Solaris, HP-UX, Linux), VMS
Data Base Systems Oracle [...] Ingress, Sybase, MS Access, Informix 7.x
Middleware Apache, Tomcat, Jboss, Weblogic, [...] Oracle9ias, IIS.ODI, OBIEE
Web Development Jsp, HTML, XML
Source Code Control Visual SourceSafe, CVS, Dimension, perforce
System Design Erwin, Visio, Oracle Designer
IDE Environments Developer-2000, PowerBuilder-4, VisualBasic-5, Gupta SQL
Office Automation Microsoft Office
Project Management MS Project

Miscelleneous SQL*Plus, SQL*Loader, Samba, Toad, VeritasNetBackup Hardware HP9000, SUN Systems, VAX-4300, ALPHA Systems, IBM PCs